

# **OBJECTIVE**

The purpose of my masters is to gain research experience in the fields of additive manufacturing technologies, machine learning, and advanced materials through coursework, projects, and faculty collaborations. After graduating, I seek to apply this expertise to various use cases in the industry. My long-term career interests lie in pioneering data-driven disruptions in additive manufacturing via machine learning.

# **EDUCATION**

### Pennsylvania State University

State College, USA

Master of Science in Additive Manufacturing & Design

August 2022 - May 2024 (Expected)

**Relevant Coursework:** Metal Additive Manufacturing, Scientific Principles of Additive Manufacturing, Metal Additive Manufacturing Lab, Non-Destructive Evaluation for Additive Manufacturing, Design for Additive Manufacturing (DfAM)

# Birla Institute of Technology and Science, Pilani

Goa, India

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechanical Engineering

*August 2017 - August 2021* 

**Relevant Coursework:** Production Planning & Control, Advanced Composites, Energy Management, Production Techniques, Engineering Optimization, Quality Control & Reliability, IC Engines, Product Design, Machine Design and Drawing, Material Science and Engineering, Supply Chain Management, Micro-Electro-Mechanical Systems (MEMS), Power Plant Engineering

**MOOCs:** IBM Data Science Professional Certificate offered by IBM on Coursera, DeepLearning.AI TensorFlow Developer(Certificate) offered by Deeplearning.ai on Coursera, SAS Statistical Business Analyst offered by SAS on Coursera

# **FACULTY RESEARCH & PROJECTS**

ML for Defect Detection in Additive Manufacturing under Dr. Edward Reutzel and Dr. Jan Petrich(Ongoing).

- Used Computer Vision techniques on XCT Data to detect porosity defects in test samples.
- Ongoing application of Computer Vision on Electro-Optical sensor feeds for defect detection.

Long-Term Creep testing of Roto-Moulded Polymers under Dr. Sachin Waigaonkar.

- We analyzed the long term creep of Rotation Moulded Polymers to determine creep coefficient for long-term use through lab experiments.
- We were accurately able to measure the creep coefficients and pass on the conclusions to our industry partners.

## OIT Testing of Polymers under Dr. Sachin Waigaonkar

- We analyzed the Oxidation Inductive Test times of various different polymers to determine their suitability for complex, time-consuming moulding processes.
- With this analysis, we were able to to find determine the polymers suitable for recycling and passed on the information to our industry partners.

#### Analysis and redesign of a moulded product failing in the field under Dr. Sachin Waigaonkar

- We analyzed a rotation moulded product failing in the field using CAD/CAE tools like ANSYS and PTC Creo
  to determine the cause of failure. We then redesigned the product such that it would not fail in the field with a
  minimum increase in cost.
- This model was then passed on to our industry partner who implemented the changes and reported on the success of the project.

# **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

# MENTORING EXPERIENCE

- o I mentored freshman students as part of the Peer Mentorship Program in my sophomore year.
- Every single mentee of mine cleared their freshman year without failing a single course.

### COMPETITIONS

#### **SAE BAJA 2019**

- o I was part of the Chassis Division at SAE BAJA BITS Goa chapter. I helped design the chassis in Solidworks, analyze it in ANSYS and build it using novel manufacturing techniques.
- We ranked 19th in the design phase.

#### SAE Aero 2020

- o I was the manufacturing head at the newly formed SAE Aero BITS Goa chapter. I helped design, analyze and manufacture the aircraft using manufacturing methods like 3D printing.
- We ranked 5th in the presentation and 20th overall.

# INDEPENDENT PROJECTS

## Blockchain Chain Analyzer

December 2022 - January 2022

- o I created a chain analyzer to identify the type of wallets holding assets of a particular protocol on Ethereum and it's associated L2 blockchains using DeBank and FTMscan APIs.
- o I applied machine learning algorithms on these wallets to cluster these wallets into categories for analysis.

## **Optimal Business Location Analysis**

October 2020 – February 2021

- Created a machine learning model to look at the geographical density of businesses (Coffee shops in this example) and find underserved clusters where a business could be expected to generate a profit.
- Identified the areas in Bangalore where coffee shops could be set up with minimal competition.

# **INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE**

**Airmeet** Bangalore, India

Data Science Intern

January 2021 – June 2022

- I worked in the Revenue Operations (RevOps) in an analyst role and later in the Analytics team in a data science role.
- In the RevOps team, I created Go-To-Market strategies, competitor Analyses and client data enrichment for shaping the company's sales strategy.
- In the Analytics team, I created machine learning models to analyze vast amounts of data; Some of these models types being: Time-Series Analysis, Regression, Natural Language Processing, and Clustering analysis. I also created automated data pipelines to facilitate easy data retrieval for analysis.

Mentor:Mr. Shardul Walwadkar

#### Aditya Birla Insulators

Halol, Gujarat, India

Analyst Intern

May 2019 - July 2019

- o I worked with the management team at the Aditya Birla Insulators plant at Halol, Gujarat in the Polymer Manufacturing division as an Analyst intern.
- I analyzed the production process and highlighted inefficiencies for throughput improvement.

### **SCORES**

### Graduate Record Examination (GRE)

*November 5, 2021* 

*September 11, 2021* 

Score: 329/340

Verbal: 162/170, Quantitative: 167/170, Analytical: 4/6

#### Test of English as a Foreign Language (TOEFL)

• Score: 115/120

Reading: 30/30, Listening: 30/30, Speaking: 29/30, Writing: 26/30